LILY THOMAS: January the 8th, 1963.
Official statement
of Mrs Flora Solomon
of 19 Spencer Square, Kensington.
Erm...
Before I-I begin, erm...
..I'd like to make it clear,
I... I didn't go to MI5.
You came to me.
All because of
a private conversation...
..or at least one that
I was lead to believe was private...
with a friend.
And, as unlikely as it may sound,
I have known Kim Philby
for a very long time...
..and, erm...
..I simply didn't put...
two and two to...
I still can't quite believe that...
I very much regret
that it has taken me all these years
to realise who he really is...
..and the despicable, hateful things
he's done.
PAPER RUSTLES
I'm sorry, Nick.
I know you always considered Kim
a close... I'm fine.
DOOR OPENS
Fine.
You should know,
Mrs Solomon's statement to MI5
is the final piece of the puzzle
that confirms everything
that Golitsyn told us when
he defected in Helsinki last year.
I read his debrief file.
He only ever mentioned
an unidentified Soviet agent.
I have a team standing by
to go to Beirut first thing.
But what you're now telling me
is that, in fact,
Golitsyn specifically identified Kim
as the traitor?
PHONE RINGS
A team from MI5?
That'll never fucking work.
CAR HORNS BEEP,
PEOPLE CHATTER
Kim has to be handled by SIS,
not MI5.
That would be madness.
And by "SIS"...
I mean me.
Utter bloody madness.
'I disagree, Sir Roger.'
Philby must, for the time being,
be viewed and treated
as a potential asset.
He must be handled with care
by an SIS man
for foreign intelligence purposes,
not arrested by MI5
for criminal prosecution.
Forgive me, but... ten years ago,
when MI5 suspected Philby
of helping Burgess and Maclean
escape to Moscow,
you, as I recall...
..were his staunchest ally.
So, I'll say it again -
sending you to Beirut
would be a colossal mistake.
KNOCK ON DOOR
Hello, Kim.
I rather thought it would be you.
CAR HORNS BEEP
Bet you wish
you were still in Beirut.
PHILBY RETCHES
E! Zakhodim v port.
Dvadtsat' minut do stykovki.
In English, please.
Russia, huh? Russia!
HE PANTS
TYPEWRITERS CLICK
AND PING
HE GRUNTS
We can send a man...
into space, but...
Ah.
I wouldn't shut that all the way
again if I were you.
Oh, right. Well, is there
another room I can use...?
It's the damp.
Expands the wood, see.
This is all there is, I'm afraid.
PHONE RINGS DISTANTLY
Don't forget, curtain's at eight.
ON TAPE: 'What theatre?'
'That'd be telling.
Spoil the surprise.
'Nice try, though.'
Go.
'We'll get through this.
'I believe in you.'
Kiss me.
CHURCH BELLS TOLL
BELLS CHIME
THEY CHAT INDISTINCTLY
Uh-oh. Don't tell me - we lost.
What?
The cricket, Tim, the cricket.
Actually, it was a draw.
England were 223 for four.
Thanks to Barrington, who was 134,
not out. Hm.
DOOR RATTLES
Oh, give it a good, hard...
Always forget about that.
You think I'd know by now.
Mr Elliott.
It's been like that as long as I can
remember. You must be Mrs Thomas...
How do you do?
..of MI5 fame.
Hardly.
Ah...
What?
We need another chair.
Hello?
How do you do?
Hello.
Tim Milne.
My instructions are to debrief
Mr Elliott alone. Ah.
Well, what you need to understand,
Mrs Thomas,
is that Mr Elliott is one of
SIS's most respected officers,
and C has asked me to sit in
and make sure that everything is,
er...
..you know...
Tickety-boo.
May I speak freely?
In this building (?)
My orders are
to debrief Mr Elliott alone
with no SIS involvement
or assistance,
but should you need clarification,
I'm to ask you to...
..call this number.
Before you go,
is there someone here...
..who might be able to do something
about that door?
There's a good fella.
Mr Elliott, I'd like to begin
by saying how sorry I am.
I realise how painful this must be
for you and everyone else here
at the Intelligence Service
who counted Mr Philby as a friend...
..and trusted colleague...
..for such an awfully long time.
Is that Northumberland I hear?
You and Mr Philby were friends
for, what, 25 years?
23.
Could you please explain to me how
he was able to escape from Beirut?
Smart money's on a boat.
No, thank you.
Newcastle...
..the accent?
Mr Elliott...
..I completely understand
why you might need a moment or two
to break the ice - believe me, I do.
Would you mind
if we now consider it broken?
The word "escape"...
would suggest that
Philby was in some sort
of custody, which he was not.
But I do understand
the drive of your question,
and the answer is this -
I simply didn't think he'd run.
I was offering him complete immunity
and secrecy,
with a nice little retirement in the
country with his wife and children,
for a full confession of everything
he ever did for the KGB.
I didn't for a moment think
he'd choose Russia over that.
Durham. My accent.
Ah. Mr Elliott, you are aware
that we have all the...
..34 hours of recordings
of you and Philby in that flat?
ON TAPE: 'Hello, Kim.'
PHILBY: 'I rather thought
it would be you.'
What did he mean by that,
"I rather thought it would be you"?
I don't know.
If you were to guess?
Well, that would be playing
his game,
and I'd sooner not do that
at this juncture. Game?
'Come on in.'
DOOR CLOSES
Can I offer you some tea?
You look a little peaky.
How's your health?
Oh, it's... perfectly tolerable,
despite recent bouts of flu
AND bronchitis.
Oh, nasty.
Yes, they were both against me.
Ah, little did they know.
I must say, I'd rather hoped "tea"
was code for something
a little stronger.
LIQUID POURING
Kim, I don't have time
to postpone this and...
we've known each other forever,
so...
if you don't mind,
I'll get right to the point.
Oh, bloody hell.
Would you believe it?
I've left my pipe at home.
Ah...
Ah, good man.
I came to tell you that your past
has caught up with you.
Oh?
We found additional information
about you
that puts everything in place.
And now... even I'm convinced,
absolutely convinced...
..that you worked for
the Soviet intelligence service...
..right up until the end of the war.
TAPE DECK CLICKS
Within the first few minutes
of the tape,
you state loud and clear,
as if for the record
and anybody else
who might be listening,
that he stopped spying for
the Soviets at the end of the war.
Yes.
Did he?
So, that was a lie.
A nuance...
A nuance.
..to protect the relationship
with our American cousins
who, I assumed,
had to be listening...
Not as far as I know.
..or would get hold of the tape.
Again, to my knowledge...
Because if they ever discovered
that he had been active for the KGB
all the way up to now,
especially during his stint
in Washington from '49 to '51...
They'd be out for blood.
Not just HIS blood.
So, am I right in saying
that you were letting him know
from the beginning you were willing
to protect him from the Americans?
I'd... rather like to think
of it as protecting the service...
And the country.
..whilst, at the same time...
..trying to offer him
every incentive to tell the truth.
By the way, why wasn't he
in some sort of custody?
Well, that's not how we...
I was trying to appeal
to his better nature.
As an Englishman.
And husband.
And father.
How did you and he first meet?
Not sure what that has to do
with what happened in Beirut.
Oh, er, wh-what happened
in Beirut...
..erm, is that the most dangerous
Soviet penetration agent
this country's ever known legged it
on your watch.
Odds are to the Soviet Union,
who, just a few months ago,
aimed missiles at America from Cuba.
So we - you and I -
are gonna look into
every single nook and cranny
of yours and Philby's friendship.
ANNOUNCEMENT
OVER TANNOY
METAL DOOR SLIDES
How do you do, Comrade Philby?
Or I should say... Agent Stanley?
I'm Sergei.
May I...?
I'd like to begin with an apology.
Is not necessary.
Even so...
You are sorry
that your hand was forced in Beirut
and that you had to escape
to Soviet Union.
Actually,
what I'd like to apologise...
I say... apology is not necessary.
First... you are KGB hero
for work as penetration agent
into British and American
intelligence since '34.
'33.
Second...
we keep you active too long.
In all honesty, I would've liked
to have gone on forever.
And to never leave England.
To never underestimating
the English again.
GLASS THUNKS
ON TABLE
SIGHS
I first met him in 1940.
'At my club.
'My closest childhood chum
had just been shot down and killed
'by the Luftwaffe.'
The first thing I noticed about Kim
was that he had this capacity
to draw people in...
and sort of appeared,
just in how he carried himself,
to know things no-one else knew...
LAUGHTER AND CHATTER
Thank you, sir.
'..exuding what I can only describe
as this very British confidence
'that everything would be all right
in the end.'
They were not in any...
EXPLOSION
That was, as it happens,
the first night of the Blitz.
STAGGERED BREATHING
All right there, old bean?
Your hand.
GASPS
GLASS SMASHES
Ups-a-daisy!
Arms, legs, all present and correct.
You couldn't scare us up
a couple of pink gins, could you?
Are you a member, sir?
What?
I'm sorry, sir,
only members are allowed to...
Put it on my bill, Sam.
He didn't seem
at all rattled by the near miss.
Which I have to say at the time
was really rather reassuring.
Kim Philby.
Do you think Philby
was playing you...
from the very first moment
that you met?
No.
I don't know.
You didn't ask him that in Beirut?
That would've been the first thing
I'd have asked him...
..if I hadn't killed him first.
So...
..why it was so easy for you
to escape SIS in Beirut?
I wouldn't exactly call it "easy".
'Mr Philby?'
Mr Philby? Sir?
Breakfast.
From... a friend.
After I received the warning
in Beirut from Moscow Centre,
I first had to see if there was
a way to weather the storm.
'After all, ten years ago, I managed
to survive a full-force hurricane...
'..brought on by Donald Maclean
and Guy fucking Burgess.'
PHONE RINGS
Philby.
Oh, hello, Peter.
No, no, no, wide awake.
The next morning, Peter Lunne,
our Beirut station chief,
he rang to invite me to tea that
afternoon at his secretary's flat,
which, as I'm sure you know,
is code for one of the safe houses.
KNOCK ON DOOR
But when Nicholas Elliott
opened the door,
I'll admit, I was caught
more than a little off-guard.
I rather thought it would be you.
Come on in.
He looked like he wanted to kill me.
And four days later, you confess?
That's not exactly
how I'd put it, no.
A typed, signed confession, no?
After four days
of denying everything...
and getting nowhere,
I felt my time was running out.
I needed to give him something
to get him to drop his guard.
So, yes, I signed, which you would
know, if you'd actually seen it,
what amounted to
a few pages of chicken feed.
No more.
To give myself an opening,
a chance to make a move
before this whole...
bloody nightmare got any worse.
Why did they send Elliott to Beirut?
Knowing him,
he talked them into it.
SONG: 'Colours Out Of Grey'
CHATTER
PHONE RINGING
CLEARS HIS THROAT
MAN: 'Hello?'
Speak.
'Elliott met a Russian
in a cemetery.
'Handed him a newspaper.
'Now I'm watching that same Russian
sitting in a coffee shop.'
'Well, stay on him.
'And do not fucking lose him.'
How long were you
and Nicholas Elliott friends?
Since 1940.
When you were both already in SIS?
Different sections.
I ran operations
in the Iberian Peninsular,
he covered Holland.
Friends... for over 20 years.
Not easy.
Requires a certain
attention to detail, I suppose.
Hard to believe he never suspected.
You must understand...
A friendship
within the British ruling class...
it's built on an ingrained belief
that victory over one's enemy
is preordained, God given.
When you think about it,
it's really remarkable,
the... the level of sentimentality
and arrogance that it must take
in order to be so wilfully blind
to the possibility that one of your
own might see things differently.
CHEERING AND APPLAUSE
Tony's the only one
who knows the words!
Happy new year, darling.
Happy new year.
Happy new year, old socks.
To peace, at last.
To us.
And to getting away with it.
KIM CHUCKLES
Why did you let him go?
I didn't. He ran.
At night.
He waited until after dark.
That's all it took?
Do you not think that in hindsight,
perhaps MI5 should've gone
to Beirut, not you?
Kim gave me an eight-page,
signed confession,
that he never would've given
anyone from MI5.
Ooh, right, yeah.
Sorry, you mean this?
Yeah.
Er... Yeah.
Isn't this what you SIS chaps call,
er... "chicken feed"?
Or is there something
you're not telling me?
When I...
grasped the scope of his betrayal...
..I realised that our friendship
had led, over the years, to...
..the deaths of hundreds...
..possibly thousands of people
at the hands of the Soviets.
Try to imagine for a moment,
if you will...
..how that might feel, and...
..give me one good reason
why I'd deliberately let him go.
I can give you several.
Firstly, you were friends for years.
Second, there's his wife
and children, not to mention SIS,
all of whom I'm sure you wanted
to protect from a public scandal.
So I have to ask if the two of you
came to some sort of quid pro quo
out there in Beirut?
I'm sorry, I need...
DOOR RATTLES
Fucking thing!
It's all right. I can manage.
HEAVY BREATHING
METAL CLANGS
HE PANTS
SIGHS WITH RELIEF
# There's one pet I like to pet
# And every evening, we get set
# I stroke it every chance I get
# It's my girl's pussy... #
SHE GIGGLES
# Seldom plays and never purrs
# And I love the thoughts it stirs
# But I don't mind
Because it's hers... #
Elizabeth Holberton,
one of my gals on the Iberia desk.
She's fluent in French,
Spanish, German, Italian...
110 words a minute.
Don't pretend you weren't ogling.
SHOUTS: Elizabeth? Over here!
# In giving thrills, never mean! #
What are you doing?
Deep breath, old bean.
I'm pretty sure she doesn't bite.
Elizabeth, may I introduce to you
my dearest and most eligible friend,
Nicholas Elliott.
GLASS SMASHES
Nick!
MAN: All right, old chap?
'Are you all right? Nick!
'Somebody get a bloody doctor!'
SIGHS
In 1951...
..you helped Comrades Burgess
and Maclean escape from the West
to the Soviet Union.
In a manner of speaking.
At great... personal risk.
When I found out the codebreakers
were onto Maclean,
there was no indication
Burgess was also blown.
Maclean had no choice.
He was blown. He had to run -
no question about it.
Burgess, on the other hand,
he was safe.
But he panicked
and decided to run anyway.
And because he'd just been
my house guest in America,
drying out for a couple of months...
The British suspected
you were also a... traitor?
You don't like that word.
GRAND THEME MUSIC
REPORTER: Mr Harold Philby,
on the right,
holds a press conference
to deny charges that he was involved
in the disappearance
of Burgess and Maclean.
The 43-year-old
former Foreign Office diplomat
has challenged his accuser, an MP,
to repeat the charges
outside the Commons.
Mr Philby.
Mr MacMillan, the Foreign Secretary,
said there was no evidence that
you were the so-called "Third Man"
who allegedly tipped off
Burgess and Maclean.
Are you satisfied with
that clearance that he gave you?
Yes, I am.
Well, if there WAS a third man,
were you, in fact, the third man?
No, I was not.
Do you think there was one?
No comment.
Mr Philby, the disappearance
of Burgess and Maclean
is almost as much of a mystery today
as it was when they went away -
about four years ago or more.
Can you shed any light on it at all?
No, I can't.
In the first place, I'm debarred
by the Official Secrets Act
from saying anything
that might disclose...
WOMAN TRANSLATES
IN RUSSIAN ON TAPE
..information
derived from my position
as a former government official.
In the second place,
the Burgess-Maclean affair
has raised issues of great delicacy
in the sphere
of international affairs.
And the Foreign Secretary
has said that in the past,
you had communist associations.
Is that why
you were asked to resign?
I was asked to resign
because of an imprudent association.
That was your association
with Burgess. Correct.
What about these alleged
communist associations?
Can you say anything about them?
The last time
I spoke to a communist,
knowing him to be a communist,
was sometime in 1934.
That rather implies that you've also
spoken to communists unknowingly
and you now know about it.
Well, I spoke to Burgess last
in April or May of 1951.
Would you still regard Burgess,
who...
lived with you
for a while in Washington,
would you still regard him
as a friend of yours?
How do you feel about him now?
I consider his action deplorable.
On the subject of friendship,
I prefer to say
as little as possible,
because it's very complicated.
A virtuoso performance.
Good God.
Are you suggesting
what I think you are?
What really happened in Beirut
between you and Nicholas Elliott?
You are. You're calling me a liar.
Who will go down in history.
DOOR OPENS,
CLOSES
Eternal Father...
whose son Jesus Christ
was sent to the throne of Heaven...
that he might rule over all things
as Lord and King...
..keep the church in the unity
of the spirit
and in the bond of peace...
and bring the whole created order
to worship at his feet,
who is alive and reigns with you
in the unity of the Holy Spirit.
One God, now and forever.
Amen.
CONGREGATION: Amen.
And now will you join me
in the Lord's Prayer?
CONGREGATION: Our Father
Which art in heaven
Hallowed be thy name
Thy kingdom come
Thy will be done
On Earth as it is in heaven...
KNOCK ON DOOR
Thought you might like a cuppa.
Thank you.
DOOR CLOSES
Mm, just a drop.
WHISPERS: Sorry. Thank you.
I'm diabetic.
Sometimes,
I forget to take my medicine -
don't tell my wife -
and gets the better of me.
We were talking about...
I know what we were talking about.
Squashed fly?
Thank you.
DISTANT CHURCH BELLS
There was no quid pro quo.
No final act of friendship.
No.
SHE HUMS
What made you go into intelligence?
We were on the brink of war,
and I wanted to do my bit...
without doing all that marching
and square-bashing,
if at all... possible.
I won't have time
to get to the shops today...
..and my husband always forgets.
SHE GRUNTS
When I was seven, my parents
sent me off to boarding school.
A brutal place that reeked
of floor polish and custard.
Sometimes, at night,
when everyone was asleep,
I'd climb out on the roofs,
where I'd imagine that
I was the Count of Monte Cristo...
..and plot my enemies' downfall
by means of surveillance,
disinformation, sabotage.
Why did Philby spy for the Russians?
Espionage can at times be...
intoxicating.
'But where the thrill
of fooling your enemy
'might be enough for most of us,
'it is not, it appears,
sufficient for Kim.'
Double-crossing your friends,
lying to your fellow spies...
..must have been...
JOVIAL CHATTER
GLASS CLINKS
APPLAUSE
HE CLEARS HIS THROAT
Ah, Elliott, oh, hold on.
EXAGGERATED BRITISH ACCENT:
Oh, Elliott, oh, just the fellow.
Please, have a seat.
I would like a frank word with you.
Certainly, sir.
Does your wife know what you do?
Yes.
Er, how did that come about?
Well, she was my secretary
for two years,
and I think the penny
must have dropped.
Yes, quite so, quite, quite.
And what about your mother?
She thinks I work for something
called SIS,
which she believes stands for
Secret Intelligence Service.
Good God!
How did she come to know that?
A war cabinet... A member...
LAUGHTER
A war cabinet fell on her
at a cocktail party.
Oh, goodness! That must've caused
all sorts of damage.
A member of the war cabinet
told her at a cocktail party.
LAUGHTER
It's true. It's actually true.
But he IS a communist?
Oh. Chicken, egg...
Please.
That does not look like enemies
to me.
The reason, by the way,
I don't like the word "traitor"
is because
I'm not a fucking traitor.
I've been loyal to Marxism
and to the Soviet Union
my entire adult life.
What were you talking about here?
I don't know.
All I remember is it was getting
rather stuffy in that flat.
It was seven days ago.
We were drinking every day, and
Nicholas is nothing if not witty.
Witty?
He obviously knew
the KGB were watching
and wanted to plant exactly
these seeds of doubt in your mind.
And there?
I don't remember.
You know what it looks like to me?
I think you say...
"partners in crime".
For God's sake, man, I have not been
turned by British intelligence.
I had to run,
otherwise, they would've killed me.
I had no other option.
Do you seriously think
I wanted to come here?
I'm sorry.
Slip of the tongue.
BRIEFCASE CLASPS CLICK
I don't believe you've ever had
a slip of the tongue, comrade.
DOOR CLANGS SHUT
By "quid pro quo", what I mean is...
I'm familiar with the term.
..maybe you let him go
in exchange for something?
Some important piece
of information...
that might resurrect your career?
Wouldn't that be nice?
Or, God forbid, protect England.
I didn't let him go.
On the last day,
you both go out onto the balcony.
For four consecutive days,
you meet in that flat
for roughly eight hours a day.
Only once do you go out
onto the balcony,
for a sum total
of about three minutes.
KNOCK ON DOOR
Who is it?
TED: 'Come to look at the door
for you, miss.'
Oh, right. Erm...
Yeah, hold on a minute, please.
I wanted Kim's Russian friends,
if they were out there,
to see him and me together.
Hm.
Were you aware
that the bug in the flat
couldn't hear you
out on the balcony?
Can't say I gave it much thought.
In other words, you didn't care.
What I... cared about
was getting Kim to tell the truth.
DOOR CLANKS
Hold on, Ted!
Am I under arrest?
No.
Good.
Cos my wife's arranged tickets
for the theatre tonight.
Oh...
What are you gonna see?
She's surprising me.
Apparently, I need cheering up.
MAN: Kensington Palace Gardens,
please. Russian Embassy.
'Your typical SIS man,
as we all know,
'concurrent with his upbringing,
'considers himself to be
part of a secret, elite club,
'which, by design, has no rules.
'Because rules... by design,
are strictly for commoners...
'like us here at MI5.'
In many ways, SIS's real enemy
is a change to the status quo
that might, erm... threaten
the existence of their club.
So for them, Philby's worst crime
is that he broke
their one unwritten rule,
which is that no member
should ever do anything
that might expose them all
to the scrutiny of the peasants...
Or, God forbid, a woman.
So I wonder if Mr Elliott insisted
he be the one to go to Beirut
so that he and Philby could find
or...
Thank you.
..create some sort
of last-minute save.
DOOR CLOSES
For example...
..what if he went out there
to initiate...
an operation
to run Philby back at the KGB?
Bloody hell, you actually mean that.
For our old friend.
I'm sorry, I just don't believe...
That SIS are that devious?
If they were running Philby back
into the USSR, they'd have told us.
Well, that's sweet, Arthur.
Quite unlike you.
Or at the very least,
one would think
they'd have asked us to back off.
Leave Elliott alone.
What if he didn't even tell SIS
what he was up to?
Taxi's here.
You look stunning.
You lost him? How?
He's a pro, for sure.
He gave me the slip in the church.
Switched hat and coat.
Now he's in the fucking wind.
Long gone.
Which means he almost certainly
is not.
CHILDREN CHATTER
Hello?
ON TAPE: 'Were you aware
that the bug in the flat
'couldn't hear you
out on the balcony?'
'Can't say I gave it
too much thought.'
'In other words, you didn't care.'
'What I...'
Oh!
'..cared about...'
How long have you been there?
No. Don't let me interrupt you.
Don't be daft. Come here.
Mm.
Uh-uh - more, please.
Yeah, boy.
That... was what I needed.
Look at you!
What's the time?
I totally lost track.
I'm so sorry,
you must be starving.
Do you wanna light a fire
and I'll rustle us up some supper?
Do you want a beer, love?
BOTTLES CLINK
VIOLIN TUNING UP
Thanks, John.
Here we are.
'He's at some Russian port
on the Black Sea.'
How was work?
Flu season, you know?
And with all the long waits
these days,
which can be up to ten times
as long for my patients,
it's all I can do to stop them
from catching pneumonia, you know?
I believe in you, love.
Hm!
This is delicious. Very tasty.
Stew left over from the other day.
VIOLIN: 'Are You Lonesome Tonight?'
BAND JOINS IN
LAUGHTER
# Are you lonesome tonight?
# Do you miss me tonight?
# Oh! Are you sorry
# We... We drifted apart? #
What you doing?
Well, I-I'm singing, aren't I?
# Are you... #
INHALES SHARPLY
LAUGHTER
MAN: Boom!
Give 'em an "ooh", Sid.
Ooh!
LAUGHTER
Didn't wanna part with that,
did you?
I'll give you a two-in, here we go.
A one... two...
A boom. Ooh!
Ya-ta-ta-tah.
# Are you lonesome tonight? #
A boom. Ooh! Ya-ta-ta-tah.
# Do you miss me tonight? #
# Are you sorry we drifted... #
Just... Just... No, stop!
Boom!
A boom...
A boom.
Just a little.
I'm ya-ta-ta-tah-ing, you see.
Oh, of course.
No, you shouldn't be.
No, I should be singing
Are You Lonesome Tonight?
Cos you've got the sideboards.
You're the star.
I go right down to here.
There's something gone wrong
with the star.
Oh, I know!
Sid - you start us off.
Give us the one-two, will you?
Then you'll be all right.
A one, two...
A boom. Ooh.
Ya-ta-ta-tah!
# Are you lonesome tonight?
A boom. Ooh. Ya-ta-ta-tah!
# Do you miss me tonight?
# Are you sorry we drifted apart? #
A boom. Ooh. Ya-ta-ta-tah!
A boom. Ooh.
Ya-ta-ta-tah!
PHILBY, SOMBRE:
# Does your memory stray
# To a bright, sunny day
# When I kissed you
# And called you sweetheart?
# Do the chairs in your parlour
# Seem empty and bare?
# Do you gaze at your doorstep
# And picture me there?
# Is your heart filled with pain?
# Shall I come back again?
# Tell me, dear
# Are you lonesome tonight? #
SILENCE
I interviewed this man today...
It's OK, my love. I know you're
not allowed to talk about your work.
..who's just found out that
his best friend of over 20 years...
..has been betraying him all along.
How long?
23 years.
And he only just found out?
You were spot on. CIA.
Angleton?
James Jesus in the flesh.
Let's keep that
under our hats for now.
Are you trying to get me killed?
Now, there's a thought.
You don't really mean that.
Give me one good reason
why not, Kim.
And it better be a fucking good one.
You know, Nick...
..we're all wondering
what happened in Beirut.
And I for one find it hard to
believe you came back empty-handed.
Subtitles by accessibility@itv.com